The Breadwinner is a animation, war, drama film directed by Nora Twomey.
A headstrong young girl in Afghanistan, ruled by the Taliban, disguises
herself as a boy in order to provide for her family.
Parvana (voice), played by Saara Chaudry.
Shauzia (voice), played by Soma Bhatia.
Idrees / Sulayman (voice), played by Noorin Gulamgaus.
Fattema / Old Woman (voice), played by Laara Sadiq.
Nurullah / Talib Security Man (voice), played by Ali Badshah.
Soraya (voice), played by Shaista Latif.
The Breadwinner is a 2017 animated drama film directed by Nora Twomey, and written
by Anita Doron and Deborah Ellis, based on the 2001 novel by Ellis.
The film was an international co-production between
Canada, the Republic of Ireland and Luxembourg.
The film had its world premiere at the 2017 Toronto International Film Festival on
8 September 2017 and received a limited release on 17 November.
It received positive reviews from critics and received a nomination
for Best Animated Feature at the 90th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, arranged
marriage, cartoon, imprisonment, afghanistan.
The tone is emotional.